

# Jimmy Alejandro Plazas López

COMPUTER AND SYSTEMS ENGINEERING | ANDROID DEVELOPER

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR'S DEGREE:**

Computer and Systems Engineering.

Pedagogical and Technological University of Colombia (Universidad Pedagógica y Tecnológica fde Colombia - UPTC) - <u>Diploma</u>.

#### TAFE:

System technique.

National Learning Service (Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje - SENA) - <u>Diploma</u>.

## **HIGH SCHOOL:**

Magdalena Educational Institution (Institución Educativa Magdalena) - <u>Diploma</u>.

# OTHER CERTIFICATIONS:

• Essential Kotlin Course: Clean Code and Functional Programming.

Udemy - <u>Certificate</u>.

Object Oriented Design and SOLID

Principles with Kotlin.

Udemy - Certificate.

- Mobile App Development Google Activate - <u>Certificate</u>.
- Java tutorial course
  Sololearn <u>Certificate</u>.

# LANGUAGES:

- Spanish Native
- English Upper intermediate (B2)

## **CONTACT ME:**

+61 0450 456138. jimmyale3102@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have been developing Android apps for three years as a passionate and motivated professional. I enjoy embracing fresh challenges with enthusiasm and a positive mindset aligned with the company's goals.

Additionally, I am a team player who enjoys building up a collegial atmosphere. My positive attitude extends to my willingness to mentor colleagues when needed. I consider myself a responsible and loyal person with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

I am eager to expand my knowledge of new technologies and keep up to date with the latest terminology in the field so as to contribute to the fast-paced world of technological advancements.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Android Mobile Developer Jr Adv, Globant, May. 2022 - Mar.
 2023

**Responsibilities:** Building an Android App in Kotlin applying clean architecture and MVVM with Jetpack Compose. Besides this, collaborating with my team to fix bugs or to add new features. Additionally, mentoring and solving the questions of my colleages.

· Android Developer, FletX, Nov. 2021 - May. 2022

**Responsibilities:** Development and maintenance of some android applications in Kotlin and Java obtaining data from API's. Working with MVVM architecture, retrofit, material design and Google Maps.

· Android Mobile Developer, BPSmart, Mar. 2020 - Nov. 2021

Responsibilities: Developing Android applications in Kotlin language integrated with Firebase. Applying endpoint consumptions, Intent calls (calendar, calls, webviews, whatsapp) and device services such as: location, internet, reading/writing for images and videos. Use of Material Design towards the design side. Integration of payment gateways. Use of Github and Git, handling of some essential commands for version control.

# **SKILLS**

**Android:** Kotlin, Jetpack Compose, Clean Architecture, Flow, Corutines, LiveData, Material Design, Java, Retrofit, MVVM architecture, DataBinding.

**Tools:** Android Studio, Firebase, Git, GitHub, Jira, GitLab, Google Play Console, Postman, ClickUp, Slack.